Matthew Weigel

Goose Creek, SC 29445 matthew.t.weigel@gmail.com 843.327.6796

Committed and hardworking Computer Science graduate seeks position as entry-level software developer. Creative problem-solver and fast learner. Years of customer service experience as a frontend service clerk cashiering and assisting customers.

Work Experience

Software Engineer for AI Training Data

Outlier - Remote June 2024 to Present

- Evaluate the quality of Al-generated responses, writing comprehensive human-readable summaries and feedback to ensure accuracy and coherence for training of large language model
- Demonstrate attention to detail by thoroughly reviewing Outlier documentation and providing clear and quality justifications when comparing code samples

Handyman

Self Employed - Summerville, SC June 2019 to Present

- Complete repair projects
- Help with organization and decluttering around the house
- Perform basic landscaping tasks such as gardening, pulling weeds, and watering
- · Assembled and installed new furniture to improve comfort and functionality
- Installed cabinets and shelving units to provide additional space and organization
- Installed lighting fixtures to improve lighting

Front Service Clerk/Cashier

Publix Super Markets - Summerville, SC August 2017 to August 2021

- · Greeted visitors and customers upon arrival, offered assistance and answered questions
- Answered questions about store policies and addressed customer concerns
- Promoted customer loyalty and consistent sales by delivering friendly service and knowledgeable assistance
- Trained new employees on warehouse protocols and answered task-related inquiries to help with job role adjustment
- · Worked closely with shift manager to solve problems and handle customer concerns
- Efficiently operated cash register for cash, check, and credit card transactions
- Checked identification for proof-of-age for alcohol and tobacco sales
- Immediately cleaned all spills on sidewalks and floors to prevent customer and employee injury
- · Placed customers' purchased goods into bags, maximizing space while avoiding overloading
- Assisted customers by escorting and placing grocery bags in vehicles
- Performed general cleaning duties by washing windows, sweeping and mopping floors, cleaning bathrooms and dusting displays
- · Supported team members and management by going above and beyond to meet goals

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science with Math Minor

Charleston Southern University - Charleston, SC August 2019 to December 2023 3.65 GPA

Skills

- · Analytical skills
- Back-end development
- C
- C++
- CSS
- · Critical thinking
- · Collaboration and teamwork
- · Customer service and assistance
- Debugging
- Dependable and responsible
- Effective communication
- Front-end development
- GitHub
- · Google Docs proficiency
- HTML
- Java
- JavaScript
- Linux
- · Listening skills
- Managing multiple tasks

- Operating systems
- Perl
- PHP
- Problem-solving skills
- Project management and support
- Python
- Qt Creator
- · Ruby on Rails
- SDLC
- · Software development
- SOI
- · System and program design
- · Testing and debugging
- · Troubleshooting and Resolution
- Ubuntu
- User-interface design
- Visual Basic
- · Web development
- Windows
- · Writing documentation

Links

http://www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-weigel-a9370a2b0

https://csuniv.joinhandshake.com/stu/users/25817525